SENIOR

AWS DEVOPS / SOLUTION ARCHITECT

Name: ANTON K.

Anton is a Senior AWS DevOps with 16+ years of commercial experience. He offers expertise in AWS services, including EC2, S3, RDS, Lambda, and ECS, as well as a strong analytical ability, incident management skills and deep knowledge in software and network/server administration. Anton has deep knowledge in networking and security best practices in cloud environment, strong understanding of the principles of scaling, load balancing and availability. Anton has an extensive experience as a team lead managing a team of developers.

EDUCATION/CERTIFICATIONS

- 2012, University Master's Degree, Computer Networks & Telecommunication
- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate
- Oracle Cloud Infrastructure 2023 Certified Multicloud Architect Assoiate
- Windows Server 2008 and Active Directory Domain Services Administrator (M6425)
- MS Exchange Server 2010 Administrator (M6425)
- Cisco Certified Network Associate Exploration
- Zabbix 5.0 Certified Specialist

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Automating infrastructure deployment and management: CloudFormation, Terraform, and Ansible
- Containerization and orchestration: ECS, Fargate, and Kubernetes
- Managing and maintaining CI/CD pipelines: CodeBuild, CodePipeline, and Jenkins
- Monitoring and logging: CloudWatch, Elasticsearch, and Kibana
- **Securing infrastructure and applications:** AWS security services (IAM, Security Groups, and KMS)
- **Scripting languages:** Python, Bash
- Databases: Oracle DB, PostgreSQL, MS SQL Server, MySQL
- Version Control Systems: Git
- Operating Systems: MS Windows, Linux

WORK EXPERIENCE

Aug 2020 – Present time	Senior AWS DevOps (UCGP Consult Ltd.)
	AWS infrastructure design, deployment, and management
	 Linux & Windows-based servers setup, configuration and maintenance in AWS cloud environment
	 Network Security Audits, Networks design, setup and configurations on AWS (including custom VPN solutions, DNS, DHCP etc.)
	 Zabbix + Grafana monitoring solutions design and deployment on AWS
	Ansible-based automatization configurations on AWS
	 Kubernetes & Docker-based solutions design and deployment on AWS
Jun 2014 - July 2020	Senior (Expert) DevOps Engineer (National GSM provider)
	 VMware vSphere & Huawei Fusion Computer virtualization solutions implementation
	Backup solutions setup, configuration and management
	 Linux, Ubuntu, SLES, Solaris (9, 10), CentOS, FreeBSD and Windows- based servers' setup, configuration, upgrades, maintenance & troubleshooting
	 Management and monitoring systems management and support (Huawei U2000, NCE-T, ECI Lightsoft, Tellabs INM, Juniper Junos Space, NEC PNMS, Cisco Prime)
	Ansible & Rundeck automatization design and deployment
	Zabbix + Grafana monitoring solutions design and configuration
	ELK logs management on AWS
	 Database's backup, migrations and troubleshooting (Oracle, Postgres, MS SQL, Redis) on AWS
	Managing a team of 7 DevOps Engineers
	Implementing, performance tuning, and supporting Oracle databases.
	 Performing general troubleshooting database maintenance activities including backup and recovery, capacity planning, and managing user accounts on AWS cloud
	Managing schemes, indexing, objects, and partitioning the tables.
	Managing system configurations.
	Creating data design models, database architecture, and data
	repository design for on-prem and AWS cloud environments.
Sept 2010 – June 2014	System Administration Team Lead (Nationwide Electricity Generation Company)
	Windows 2008R2, 2012 server's administration (AD, Exchange, Lync,
	TMG, Terminal Server)
	 Linux server's setup and administration (Oracle, Apache, NGINX, Syslog, Cacti, Clogin)
	Corporate network infrastructure setup and configuration (Cisco, Mikrotik) on-prem and in the cloud environment

	 Monitoring systems setup and configuration (Zabbix, Splunk)
	 VMware vShere 4.x/5.x setup and configuration (vCenter, HA, DRS
	etc.)
	 Backup systems setup and configuration (WS Backup, Cobian, Veaam 5.0 for virtual machines)
	Fujitsu Flex Frame for SAP administration
	 Storage systems administration (EMC, Netapp, Hitachi, Fujitsu
	Solaris (9,10) servers infrastructure administration
	 Managing a team of 7 DevOps Engineers/Network Administrators
	 Integration setups, web services, external databases
Sept 2007 - Sept 2010	System administrator, Network Administrator (Huge Retailer)
	Enterprise-level IT infrastructure setup, upgrades, support and
	management
	 MS Windows Server 2008 -based solutions design and deployment (AD, MS SQL, Terminal Server, Exchange, DCHP), Microsoft Dynamix AX management & support
	 Linux and FreeBSD server's administration (DNS, DHCP, Postfix, Iptables, VPN, Iproute2)
	IT infrastructure monitoring solutions design, setup and maintenance
	Network equipment configuration & troubleshooting (Cisco, Mikrotik)
	VOIP solutions implementation (Cisco, Nortel)
Nov 2006 - Aug 2007	System Administrator (Retail company)
	 W2k3 (AD, Exchange, ISA, SQL) servers' setup and administration
	Network security management
	 Communication with clients for issues clarifications, and
	troubleshooting